Guide to the Kenneth M. Reardon papers, 1971-2015.
Reardon, Kenneth M. papers
- Series IV. Major Projects
  - Cornell University
    - Press
      - North Country Press - Northside, November 26, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - Ithaca Press - Northside, 2001 - 2002, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Cornell Press, 1983, 2000 - 2003 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - University of Urbana-Champaign Press, 1992-1999 (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - Press and Events, 2003-2009 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Cornell Engaged Scholars and Urban Scholars Program (CUSP)
      - Cornell University: Bartels Action Research Fellowship, May 23, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 21)
        Includes "The Reflective Integration of Service and Learning: The Bartels Undergraduate Action Research Fellows Program, 2001-2002"
      - Cornell University: Rochester Cornell Partnership, Undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
        Includes "Enhancing the Cornell/Rochester Development Partnership. A Five-Year Strategy"
      - Hecksher Foundation, January 2002 (Box 11, Folder 23)
        Includes a proposal for an undergraduate urban internship program, program fact sheet and service learning symposium schedule.
      - Cornell Urban Scholars Program (CUSP), 2003, 2008, 2010 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Cornell Urban Scholars Program, Summer 2007 (Box 11, Folder 25)
        Includes 2007 bios of interns, fellows, staff, as well as program summaries
      - Urban Scholars Press, August 2006 - September 2006 (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Cornell Urban Mentor Initiative (CUMI), 2008 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - CUMI Meeting Notes and Handouts, August 2007 - September 2007 (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Compact Engagement, 2000 - 2001 (Box 11, Folder 29)
        Includes "Community/University Partnerships for Economic Development: A Movement Whose Time Has Come!" by Kenneth Reardon, "Higher Education Engagement in Local Economic Development: Policy Guidelines for Socially-Responsible Investment" by Kenneth M. Reardon and Pierre Clavel; Cornell Urban Scholars Program budget 2007-2010
      - Public Service & Porus, 1999 - 2000 (Box 11, Folder 30)
        Includes Memo to Dean Porus Olpadwala from Ken Reardon regarding the status of Cornell's Public Service Efforts
      - Course Proposal for NYC, 1996 - 2000 (Box 11, Folder 31)
        Includes proposals for Urban Innovation projects in NYC through community/university partnerships, by Ken Reardon such as " The Cornell University Center for Urban Innovation Projects: Re-weaving the Social Fabric of America's Most Distressed Communities"
      - Growing up in Cities: NYC, Undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Urban Scholars Program Press, May 6, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Catania/ Ithaca Partnership, November 19, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Ford Evaluation of Camden C/U partnerships, May 2001 - March 2002 (Box 11, Folder 35)
        Includes web-based surveys, "Landscape as Strategy for Development", "Collaborations that Count: Working for Democracy in Revolutionary Times"
      - "Neighbors Building Neighborhoods" Youth Community Newsletter, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 36)
        A partnership of Cornell University and Rochester
      - Proposal for Upstate Community Design Center, February 2005 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Rochester Project Press, December 18, 2000 - December 21, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Cornell Justice Center Study, June 12, 1998, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
        Includes an Initial Approval Request for an honors thesis that focuses on alternatives to incarceration
      - Community Development Series, May 13, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Includes proposal that focuses on community development, neighborhood planning and capacity building in community based organizations in East St. Louis, Illinois
      - Correspondence/ Administrative Materials, Fall 2004 - August 2007 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Urban Scholars Grant, 2004, Undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Participatory Planning Workshop, Undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Urban Programing, 1999 - 2005 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        Includes First Year Report for CUMI, press and other materials regarding Cornell's involvement in Urban areas
      - Municipal Court Clerks material and Empowerment Planning, 2005 - 2007, Undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Harlem Tour, Undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
        Includes Harlem Renaissance material
  - University of Memphis
    - South Memphis
      - South Memphis Revitalization Action Plan (The SoMeRAP), September 2009 (Box 11, Folder 39a-39c)
      - South Memphis Revitalization Action Plan Executive Summary and Presentation on Plan and Facts, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - South Memphis Renaissance Collaborative Roots, Community Planning and Visioning, 2009 (Box 11, Folder 41)
        Includes background and origins, general handouts, and presentation materials
      - Scope of Service and Grant Applications, January 20, 2009 - August 2011 (Box 11, Folder 42)
        Includes preliminary scope of service between St. Andrew's A.M.E. Church, the South Memphis Renaissance Collaborative, and the University of Memphis Department of Anthropology and School of Urban Affairs and Public Policy; scope of services for South Memphis Implementation Project; grant applications for the University of Memphis Urban Transformation Initiative, and for a South Memphis Community Education, Nutrition, and Environmental Initiative
      - Community Meeting and Stakeholder Participatory Materials, April 2008 - May 2010 (Box 11, Folder 43)
        Includes steering Committee agendas, notes, attendance sheets and contact information for community stakeholders; community organizing and neighborhood-wide meeting agendas, planning notes, schedules; meeting invitations and flyers; pulpit and bulletin announcements; May 2010 charette agenda and sign-in; letters and petitions for organizational, faith-based, and individual support for SoMeRAP; a work plan to gather support for SoMeRAP; community service award recognition by the Tennessee Medical Association for SoMeRAP and off-shoot community projects
      - Neighborhood Summit, March 23, 2009 - April 2009 (Box 11, Folder 44)
        Includes planning agendas and notes pre-summit; flyers, pulpit and bulletin announcements, sign-in sheet, agenda, meeting facilitator note guidelines, meeting evaluation form
      - Press Materials and Coverage, October 2009 - November 2009 (Box 11, Folder 45)
        Includes press conference talking points, speakers list, articles, radio call-in notes, letter to the editor template
      - Government Advocacy, November 2009 - January 2010 (Box 11, Folder 46)
        Includes South Memphis Revitalization Action Plan Resolution, advocacy talking points, correspondence, planning meeting and Land Use Control Board agendas
      - Field Work Notes, Summer 2008 - Spring 2009 (Box 11, Folder 47)
      - PLAN7006: Course Materials, Spring 2009 (Box 11, Folder 48)
      - PLAN7006: Course Readings, Spring 2009 (Box 11, Folder 49)
      - Neighborhood Profile, December 2008, Undated (Box 11, Folder 50)
        Includes student work on South Memphis Renaissance Study Area including local perceptions; SWOT and asset-based analysis; community history, and other neighborhood profile related materials
      - Neighborhood Community Stakeholder Profile: St. Andrew A.M.E. Church, Undated (Box 11, Folder 51)
        Includes St. Andrew's history, PowerPoint of their enterprise business plan, and community resources St. Andrew A.M.E. Church, a co-founder in the South Memphis Renaissance Collaborative and partner in the SoMeRAP process is a neighborhood anchor institution in South Memphis.
      - Physical Conditions Survey and Analysis, Undated (Box 11, Folder 52)
        Includes student work on existing physical conditions including land use, architectural style, building conditions, and other assessments, in addition to evaluations of proposed alternatives aimed at enhancing the physical conditions of the neighborhood
      - Field Research Materials, January 2009 - April 2009 (Box 11, Folder 53)
        Includes neighborhood tour itinerary, fieldwork guide, interview guidelines, resident interview inventory sheet, maps of resident interview service areas, student sign-up sheets and schedules for resident interviews, including a community volunteer sign-in record
      - Resident Interviews, Spring 2009 (Box 11, Folder 54)
        Includes resident interview inventories by student interviewers, resident opinion surveys drafts and final versions, Survey Monkey analysis of resident opinions; additional summary of some responses on key questions
      - Institutional Interviews, Fall 2008 - Spring 2009 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        Includes community stakeholder interview guide, two interview transcriptions from interviews with St. Andrew AME Church religious leaders, institutional interview contact list, interview questions for religious leaders, community stakeholders
      - Signature Projects Drafts, 2009, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
        Includes "Part I: Introducing the Plan and the Community", public safety initiatives, "South Memphis Revitalization Action Project Transportation", physical development, public health, and South Parkway East plan. Signature project summaries and group work documents with immediate/short, intermediate, and long-term initiatives and goals; these signature projects are featured in the final SoMeRAP
      - Parkway Plaza: South Memphis Market Study and Feasibility Analysis SPECIAL PROJECTS STUDIO, May 5, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        Includes executive summary and draft of "Parkway Plaza: South Memphis Market Study & Feasibility Analysis. Special Project Studio's market analysis study on proposed retail space based on community surveys, census tract analysis, and pro forma analysis of construction and operating costs identifying a gap between household spending power in the Parkway Plaza trade area and estimated sales of existing retailers, positive return projections and recommendations
      - Community Meeting and Stakeholder Participation Materials, May 2010 - 2011 (Box 12, Folder 4)
        Includes Steering Committee, Advisory Board, and general meeting agendas and notes; 2011 preliminary work plan for farmers market; letters (drafts and final versions) to neighbors and local pastors around the South Memphis area with an invitation to join the South Memphis Farmers Market for orientation meetings, being involved in the market's opening and a press conference, and other related outreach efforts to ensure the market is a success; brochure on 2011 season; 2011 season social activities calendar
      - Field Work and Planning Notes, June 2010 - July 2011 (Box 12, Folder 5)
        Includes Kenneth M. Reardon's hand-written field work and planning notes from meetings on the development of the South Memphis Farmer's Market, a major signature project in the SoMeRAP
      - Farmers' Market Site Plan, April 2010 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        Includes proposed site plan for South Memphis Farmers Market, an application (by The Works, Inc., a community stakeholder) for the market to be on a permanent site, includes a development budget. Additional note: Permanent site development was approved and the market opened in the summer of 2010
      - Farmers Market Vendor Materials, 2010 - 2011 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Includes materials in packet to invite farmers to participate in the market: fact sheet on the South Memphis Farmers Market; handout on the top-10 reasons on why vendors should join the market; vendor application and agreement, inclusive of proposed vendor sale items; and market season rules and regulations (draft and final versions). This folder also includes a vendor application and agreement from a local farmer from Toone, TN.
      - Farmers Market Survey Instruments, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        Included is a South Memphis Resident Health Survey Instrument filled out as a sample
      - Press Materials and Coverage, Fall 2009 - Summer 2011 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Presentations, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        "Addressing Urban Food Insecurity: Farmers Markets - Step-by-Step" and "Revitalizing South Memphis: Moving From Plans to Action". Presentation notes on the back of first presentation.
      - Tours, 2010 - 2012 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        Includes South Memphis Revitalization Action Project (SoMe RAP), Farmers Market Preliminary Work Plan, press, "Planning and Design in The Bluff City: An Urban Issues Tour", Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Initiative.
    - Brownsville
      - Brownsville on the Move: A Comprehensive Plan, December 2, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Brownsville on the Move: A Comprehensive Plan, Undated; CD-2483 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Proposed Scope of Services, Fall 2009, June 2011 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Planning Process, December 2010 - September 2011 (Box 12, Folder 13)
        Includes "Developing a Comprehensive Development Plan for Brownsville, "Scope of Services for the Brownsville/Haywood County Quality of Life Study,; U.S. Census Data for Brownsville; Focus Group findings; Graduate Assistant summer appointments for Brownsville on the Move and task lists; email correspondence from Steve Redding to schedule radio interview for Brownsville on the Move; list of objectives; list of projects; Special Projects Studio goals and objectives; Brownsville electronic survey; Planners Network International Conference "The Brownsville Greenway Initiative" Charrette; comments and recommendations from the Planners Network Charette; Preliminary Outline of the Brownsville on the Move Comprehensive Development Plan; Brownsville on the Move team contact sheet; "Appendix 2 Brownsville Community and Business Leader Survey (local institutions"; correspondence between Ken Reardon, Sharon Hayes, and David Westendorff regarding Brownsville executive summary and edits to the mission and goals, along with the attached documents; Executive Summary draft of Brownsville's Comprehensive Development Plan
      - Special Projects Studio Course Materials, January, 13 2011 - May 2011 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Workshop, May 14, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        Includes email correspondence from Kenneth Reardon regarding Brownsville workshops; PowerPoint presentation, "Brownsville on the Move: Goal and Objective Setting"; "Proposed Brownsville on the Move Goal and Objectives," with edits; Brownsville on the Move Preliminary Data Book; early work on the preliminary Data Book; "Brownsville on the Move Planning Team" contact sheet
      - Mississippi River Trail Proposal, Scope of Services, Participatory Materials, July 18, 2011 - January 31, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 16)
        Includes materials from the start of the University of Memphis' City and Regional Planning Department's first role with Professor Reardon as the principal investigator, inclusive of the proposal summary, the preliminary scope of services (for Mississippi River Corridor Trail Tennessee), the budget, the stakeholder contact list, meetings, Community Forum PowerPoint and some educational materials such as a pamphlet with maps of the trail. The Mississippi River Trail Plan connected to the Shelby County Bike Plan and other related Mississippi River projects through the national scenic by-ways initiative, urban trail planning in the Greater Memphis Region, and other plans connected to the river in neighboring states.
      - Shelby County Trail Report - Preliminary Draft, February 7, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Shelby County Trail Plan; Mississippi River Corridor, March 2011 - 2012 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Memphis Regional Design Center, Fall 2008 - January 19, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 19)
        Includes MRDC Board of Directors Committees, Board of Directors Executive Director Report, Urban Land Institute (ULI) "Exploring the Transformative Roles of Greenways", map listing existing medians "The Parkway System" and Urban Design 101 Material such as: Syllabi, Community Sustainability document
    - Vance and Green Machine
      - Vance
        - Triangle Noir, 2008 - 2009 (Box 12, Folder 20)
          Includes "Triangle Noir An Urban Renaissance Development" by the City of Memphis Housing and Community Development Housing Authority and Mayor's Executive Order.
        - Triangle Noir Press, January 2012 (Box 12, Folder 21)
          Includes PowerPoint presentation by City of Memphis Division of Housing and Community Development titled "Public Hearing" and " 'Hwy 61 - Blues Trail': Downtown Segment" Map of existing and proposed trails.
        - South of Beale Renaissance Action Project, September 2009 - December 2009 (Box 12, Folder 22)
          Includes "South of the Forum Neighborhood Revitalization Initiative", Vance Avenue Project" meetings material from various events.
        - Vance Avenue Project, Spring 2010 (Box 12, Folder 23)
          Includes "Anthropology 3282 - The Cultural History of American Communities" syllabus and planning meeting notes.
        - Preliminary Data Book - Vance Neighborhood Community Forum, December 12, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 24)
        - City's South Forum Redevelopment Plan Report and Executive Summary, Undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
        - St. Patrick's Community Outreach Center, 2008 - 2012 (Box 12, Folder 26)
          The St Patrick's Community Outreach Center (SPCOC). Includes several issues of St Patrick's newsletter, an evaluation of a student intern from the Univ. of Memphis CRP department, a draft of SPCOC bylaws, meeting agendas and materials, speech, a list of programs and materials from their annual Gipson 5k run-walk, a fundraiser for SPCOC.
        - Gibson 5k Run - Walk Memphis, 2010 - 2011 (Box 12, Folder 27)
        - UM Community Development Series, November 2007 - December 2007 (Box 12, Folder 28)
        - "Revised Social History and Contemporary Urban Issues Tour of the Vance Avenue Neighborhood", 2009 (Box 12, Folder 29)
        - Personal To-Do List for Various Projects, April 2010 - September 2010, Undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
        - Expenditure Requests Vance, February 26, 2010 (Box 12, Folder 31)
        - Vance GA Meetings, September 2011 - March 2012 (Box 12, Folder 32)
        - Community Meetings and Stakeholder Participation Materials, 2010 - 2013 (Box 12, Folder 33)
          Includes meeting agendas, notes flyers, community letters, invitations, factsheets, Asset Inventory of Vance Choice Neighborhood, "South Memphis Revitalization Action Project/Vance Avenue Project" during Virginia Tech's Spring Break and materials used in VAC (Vance Avenue Collaboration) meetings such as PowerPoint titled, "Residents Inputs for the Transformation of their Neighborhood", "Cleaborn Homes Hope VI", "Pathway to Dignity"
        - Vance Avenue Collaborative Materials and Presentations, July 12, 2011, Undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
          Includes "Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhoods Planning Initiative, Social History and Urban Issues Tour" and "Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, Threats (SWOT) Analysis"
        - Neighborhood Summit, March 2010 (Box 12, Folder 35)
        - Retreat to Highlander Center, May 31, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 36)
          Includes Grant Agreement for University of Memphis Urban Community Transformation Initiative
        - Vance Avenue Surveys, December 2009, 2011 - 2012 (Box 12, Folder 37)
        - Census and Survey Data, 2000, 2010, Undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
        - Vance Avenue Preliminary Planning Framework - Outlines and Work Plans, February 2010, Undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
          Includes Homelessness Project, Social and Health Services, and possible solutions to reduce homeless among women with children
        - Vance Avenue Preliminary Planning Framework, May 2010 - June 2010 (Box 12, Folder 40)
        - Vance Choice Neighborhood Assembly Fact book, March 31, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 41)
        - Community Assembly Materials, 1937 - 2012 (Box 12, Folder 42)
          Includes "Neighborhood Sub-Group Report", National Register of Historic Places, Multiple Property Documentation Form for "Public Housing Projects in Memphis, Tennessee 1935-1946", photocopies and media for "Administration Building at Foote Homes" under Memphis Housing Authority's control (1937 - 1997) and Neighborhood Assembly materials such as PowerPoint, agenda and evaluation forms.
        - Vance Avenue Renaissance Plan Outline, February 4, 2012, May 5, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 43)
          Includes A neighborhood improvement plan for the Vance Avenue neighborhood created through a highly participatory process facilitated by the University of Memphis City and Regional Planning department and the City of Memphis Division of Housing and Community Development.
        - Homelessness Initiative, January 13, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 44)
        - TYE: Teaching Youth Entrepreneurship, 2011, Undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
          Includes materials for the incorporation/non-profit framework and tax status of a new organization called "Teaching Youth Entrepreneurship founded by James Smith, a resident of the Vance Avenue Neighborhood. Professor Reardon assisted Mr. Smith in establishing TYE as a 501(c)3 organization; materials include tax forms, by-laws, charter, operations and strategic business plans, proposed budget, and correspondence papers
        - TYE - IRS Documentation, November 30, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 46)
        - TYE Incorporation Papers, Undated (Box 12, Folder 47)
        - Early History, Memphis, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 48)
        - Choice Best Practices Memphis, 2005, 2010 - 2012 (Box 12, Folder 49)
          Includes "Comprehensive System from Drop Inn to Permanent Support", map of Vance's site proposals, and "How to Open a Pop-Up Store"
        - Choice Neighborhood Factsheet Memphis, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 50)
        - Choice Summit Memphis, March 6, 2012 (Box 12, Folder 51)
        - UM Choice Neighborhood Meeting Materials, May 2012 - June 2012 (Box 13, Folder 1)
          Includes Foote Homes resident survey, petition and neighborhood meeting invitations.
        - Choice Neighborhood - Grant Report, November 3, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 2)
          Includes edited draft of "Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Documentation Activity" for the "Vance Avenue Choice Neighborhood Planning Grant"
        - Choice Neighborhood - Breakout Session Notes, May 10, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Choice Proposed Budgets, July 2011 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Promise Neighborhood Initiative - Vance, April 2012, Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - UM Choice Neighborhood Contract, 2010, 2012, 2013, Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Choice Neighborhood Management Team Materials, June 2011 - May 2012 (Box 13, Folder 7)
          Includes meeting agendas and notes, program schedules and reports, logos and other materials such as proposed schope of service, planning grant documents, PowerPoint report of activity, etc.. The Choice Neighborhood Management Team, which consisted of consultants/contractors on the HUD Choice Neighborhood Grant for the Vance Avenue neighborhood, and included the following entities: the Memphis Housing Authority, the City of Memphis' Housing and Community Development Division, the Neighborhood Team (the University of Memphis City and Regional Planning Department, residents, community members), the People Team (consulting firm and community service providers, etc.), and the Housing Group (developers, contractors, etc.).
        - VStrategy Meetings, July 2012 - September 2012 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - "Vance at a Crossroads", August 2012 - September 2012, Undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
          Includes correspondence seeking supporters to preserve public housing in Vance.
        - Community Redevelopment Agency (CRA) Application for Tax Increment Financing Assistance (TIF) Assistance, September 11, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 10)